

SECONDARY MATH TEACHER

15561 W. 64th Pl Unit C Arvada, CO 80007

□ 804.241.3035 | ■ phillip.n.patrick@gmail.com | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/phillipnpatrick/

About Me

I am a math teacher with 4 years of experience teaching math at the secondary level. Prior to teaching, I was a software developer for 10 years. I am currently looking for a position that will allow me to combine my skills as a teacher and as a software developer.

Education

University of Richmond Richmond, VA

MASTER OF EDUCATION - CURRICULUM & INSTRUCTION August 2016

University of Richmond Richmond, VA

POST-BACCALAUREATE CERTIFICATE OF EDUCATION (SECONDARY)

December 2014

Virginia Commonwealth University Richmond, VA

POST-BACCALAUREATE CERTIFICATE OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

December 2000

Longwood College Farmville, VA

Bachelor of Music – Piano Performance Concentration; Minor - Mathematics

December 1997

Professional Experience

The Academy of Charter Schools

MATH TEACHER August 2018 - Present

- Create notes and assessments using LaTeX
- Provide instruction in Algebra 2 and Trigonometry
- Faculty sponsor of the National Honor Society

Henrico County Public Schools (Deep Run High)

MATH TEACHER January 2015 - June 2018

- Provide instruction in the following courses: Algebra 1, Algebra 2 (Standard and Honors), Geometry (Standard and Honors), and Trigonometry
- · Prepare academically appropriate yet challenging lesson plans aligned with state standards and division specified pacing guide
- Integrate technology and 21st century skills into lesson plans
- · Collaborate bi-monthly with peers to discuss curriculum and instructional strategies
- Continue to develop teaching skills through professional development workshops

Studio 88

Owner/Piano Instructor

June 2011 - December 2014

- Private business providing private piano lessons
- Vice-president of the Richmond Music Teachers Association

The Computer Solution Company, EDI Partners, Computer Sciences Corporation

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER March 2001 - May 2011

- Designed, implemented, tested and supported large Sharepoint projects at various companies
- Designed, implemented, tested and supported InfoPath forms with C# code integrated into a Sharepoint environment
- Participated in all stages of the software development life cycle to improve the United States Navy Aegis software (i.e. implementing changes, unit testing, integration testing, functional testing, system testing).
- Developed applications written in C++ and Java that used a third-party Graphical User Interface toolkit to display real-time data in graphs, bar charts, and pie charts to allow software developers to monitor system performance.
- Worked as part of a team to collect customer requirements for software applications to develop and implement the appropriate software